# **Peter Kappus**

+44 (0) 203 468 4224 hello@peterkappus.com http://kapp.us/cv

## **Profile**

A versatile, innovative, programme/portfolio delivery manager with very strong technical and data skills, a passion for creative problem-solving and 15+ years delivering value for a range of organisations spanning bio-tech, government, automotive, banking/financial services, and advertising.

A natural servant-leader, I easily bridge the business and technology, specialising in helping teams to explore and apply innovative managerial, strateic, and technical solutions to deliver outstanding digital products & services that delight customers and increase profitability. I create a culture of continuous measurement improvement through careful critical thinking, strong interpersonal skills, and creative innovation. My strong goal-setting and strategic alignment skills (e.g. OKRs) combined with a relentless focus on commercial outcomes and financial responsibility (looking after budgets in excess of £150m) ensure outstanding results and highly engaged teams.

Possessing a naturally entrepreneurial mindset able to quickly devise and deliver innovative technological & managerial solutions to seemingly intractable problems.

## **Skills**

Lean/Agile Delivery

Adaptive risk management

Product/service management

Data analytics

Jira, Trello, Pivotal Tracker, etc.

Rapid prototyping

Cloud infrastructure (AWS)

Basic Linux DevOps

Systems thinking, cynefin

Accounting / finance

Goal Setting / Strategy

Mobile Development

Source control (git)

Portfolio/Programme Delivery

Stakeholder management

Roadmapping & reporting

Continuous delivery

Ruby / Python / Java

Scrum & kanban (CSM)

Code as infrastructure

Workshopping / facilitation

Management Information

Process design / modeling

Behaviour Driven Dev (BDD)

User Centred Design (UX)

Service Oriented Architecture

## **Experience**

## **Benefits Realisation Delivery Lead**

### **Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, UK Government)**

Nov 2016 - April 2017

Within the Common Technology Services programme which is rolling out common technology solutions such as shared wifi, shared print, etc. with stronger commercial arrangements across government.

- Enabled delivery teams to use agile methodologies to deliver benefits via rapid, continuous iteration with increased transparency
- Developed a robust, flexible and simple processes to roadmap and realise £1.5bn+ in cashable benefits over 10 years
- Built bespoke contract analysis/management tool (Ruby)
- · Used Ruby on Rails to build bespoke forecasting and tracking tools
- Enabled real-time decision-making for stakeholders and contributors
- · Clearly aligned strategy and delivery teams around concrete goals
- Dramatically streamlined internal planning/reporting process while improving transparency

Tools & Techniques: Google Sheets w/ scripting, Ruby on Rails, Google Forms, Lean/Agile cost/benefit modelling, Salesforce, etc.

## **Portfolio Delivery Manager**

### **Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, UK Government)**

Jun 2015 - Nov 2016

Through close engagement with finance, people, and delivery teams combined with strong technical ability I added significant operational agility to the business; enabling senior leadership to make informed, data-driven decisions around prioritisation, investment diversity, delivery, risk, financial performance, headcount and benefits realisation to effectively manage a £500m complex change portfolio (£150m+ in 16/17) driving digital transformation across the UK government and benefiting millions of citizens.

- Replaced complex, inflexible vendor ERP solution with bespoke BI platform
- Saved £100k+ while improving accuracy, engagement, and user satisfaction
- · Reduced reporting cycles from quarterly to monthly
- Upskilled non-technical internal team to deliver internal digital tools, processes and services to ensure ongoing improvement
- Streamlined business planning to make it light-weight, continuous, and real-time
- Introduced impact-mapping and Objectives and Key Results (OKRs)
- Created bespoke OKR tracking tool using Ruby on Rails

Technologies: Google sheets w/ heavy scripting, Google Forms, Ruby on Rails, Hyperion, Anaplan, JavaScript, and more.

## **Programme Delivery Manager**

### **Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, HM Government)**

Nov 2014 - Jun 2015

Responsible for delivering the Digital Marketplace (https://www.digitalmarketplace.service.gov.uk/), a revolutionary programme (comprising an online platform, legal & commercial frameworks, and customer support) transforming how the government buys digital. G-Cloud sales (https://www.gov.uk/performance/g-cloud) alone circa £1.4B as of July 2016.

• Active in daily delivery ceremonies (stand-ups, planning, retrospectives, etc).

- Managed multiple, complex stakeholder relationships
- Coached teams in agile methodologies, business planning and reporting: resource management, roadmapping, benefits realisation, risk mitigation, stakeholder management
- Oversaw a ~£3M annual budget for a 30+ person cross-functional team (spanning product design, user research, technology, procurement, engagement, support, legal, and analytics)
- Active participant in the Agile delivery community at GDS providing coaching, training, and mentoring across GDS

**Technology:** Pivotal Tracker, Java (Grails), Python (Flask), Jenkins, SQL Alchemy, git, Postgres, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, continuous integration (CI) with Jenkins, infrastructure automation with Ansible, AWS Relational Data Store (RDS). All code open sourced via github (https://github.com/alphagov/? utf8=%E2%9C%93&query=digitalmarketplace).

# **Delivery Manager | Agile Transformation Coach**

#### **Pearson PLC**

Jul 2013 - Nov 2014

Successfully delivered two critical, at-risk programmes by transitioning from a dysfunctional waterfal to a high-functioning, lean/agile practice using Scrum, Lean, kanban, retrospectives, rapid prototyping, user testing, etc.

- Turned stakeholders from sceptics to partners by improving efficacy, quality and time to market while reducing cost
- Demonstrated high customer satisfaction with real data
- Transitioned from legacy ITIL to modern DevOps culture
- Introduced BDD using Capybara, Cucumber, phantomJS, and more
- Delieverd complete redesign, rebuild, and platform migration of the Pearson Qualifications
  (https://qualifications.pearson.com) website (a £300M+ annual business with 60K+ pages and documents)
  from SharePoint to Adobe Experience Manager (CQ)
- Embedded lasting change: improved ways of working continue to deliver benefits today
- Delivered a real-time analytics platform using **Big Data** and **Machine Learning** to predict subscription renewal rates and identify at-risk clients
- Mentored senior stakeholders in lean/agile methodologies supporting wider digital transformation of the world's largest publishing company.

**Technologies:** Single Sign on (Forgerock), Jira, Adobe CQ (Java), Solr, AngularJS, Apache, Jenkins, Cucumber (Ruby, Capybara, Poltergeist, PhantomJS), MySQL, CouchDB, MongoDB, Python/Flask, SOA/RESTful APIs

## **Delivery Manager | Agile Coach**

### American Express (via ustwo™)

Nov 2012 - May 2013

Managed front-end/UX delivery and coached technical and leadership teams at a Fortune 100 credit-card company to deliver a large-scare customer loyalty programme spanning 14 different partner organisations.

- Led agile ceremonies across multiple teams (50+ people)
- · Responsive Web, iOS, and Android
- Multi-million dollar programme of work
- Global programme with teams in London, Boston, New York, India, Germany, and Phoenix
- Targeting 50 million households at launch
- Delivered on time with terrific reception

Tech stack included JIRA, Java EE, SDLC, SOA, Scrum, Agile, User Experience (UX), iOS, Android, Responsive Web

## **Product Owner | Data Scientist**

## **Gray Metrics**

Apr 2012 - Nov 2012

Applied agile/lean principles and engineering capability enabling a **big data start-up** to conceive and deliver a first-gen social media data mining and trend analysis platform for the automobile industry. Included market strategy, product ownership, engineering, and business development. **AWS (EC2), MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Jetty, D3.js, and R** 

## Scrum Master | Agile Coach

**JAM @ Engine People Limited** 

Aug 2011 - Mar 2012

Managed delivery of a real-time social media management and analytics platform to web and mobile channels. Servant leader to a team of engineers, designers, and business owners between the UK & South America. Provided individualised coaching to embed lasting agile transformation. JIRA, SOA, RESTful APIs, PHP, MySQL, Apache, Tomcat, Java EE, GNIP, Watir, jQuery, Automated Testing, iOS, Android, Windows Phone.

## **Delivery Manager**

Credit Suisse (via ustwo™)

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011

Managed front-end design and delivery of an award-winning **Fixed Income (forex)** Single Dealer Platform (SDP) for a **global Tier 1 investment bank** including support for **cash**, **options**, **and algorithmic trading**. Worked with multiple stake-holders across various lines of business including client services, product management, and information technology. Introduced bespoke agile design process within the bank's legacy SDLC. Employed **JIRA**, **Confluence**, **OmniPlan**, **OmniFocus**, **Axure**, **Nirvana**, **Java EE**, **XAML**, **Silverlight**, **HTML**, **CSS**, and **Javascript**.

### **Delivery Manager**

Cellnovo (via ustwo™)

Dec 2009 - Aug 2010

Managed delivery of a ground-breaking wireless web-enabled insulin pump with touch-screen UI (requiring CE Mark and EN-60601-1 compliant embedded software). Reported directly to Chief Executive Officer and liaised with in-house and vendor teams in London, Winchester, Poland, and Wales. Applied agile methods to create a robust engineering, UX, and defect management processes prior to arrival of VP of engineering. Routinely met with investors and board members. OmniGraffle, SpiraTeam, OmniPlan, C++, ANT-RF, GSM, ActionScript, WinCE, HaXe.

## **Owner, Director of Technology**

Design Commission, Inc.

Sep 2006 - Aug 2009

Managing Director/Owner of a **full-service digital design and development agency**. Increased revenue 350% and grew headcount from 2 to 12 people. Responsibile for corporate strategy, account management, business development, forecasting and budgeting, employee development and retention, project management, technical delivery, user experience, information architecture and vendor management. **Ruby on Rails, PHP, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, WordPress, ActionScript, Flash, Agile/Scrum, BaseCamp, Lighthouse, Rally, OmniFocus, OmniGraffle, GTD, Harvest, QuickBooks, MS Office, Google Analytics, Omniture, TextMate, <b>MySQL.** 

#### Founder / CTO

### **Boom Bucket Mobile**

Sep 2005 - Aug 2010

Founder and CTO of a **mobile content** start-up. Built **digital asset management** platform for ingesting, cataloging, showcasing, distributing, and reporting on thousands of mobile wallpapers and ringtones. Also responsible for **business development and marketing** including the company's 2006 launch at *Mobile World Congress* in Barcelona Spain. **HTML, ActionScript, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL.** 

### **Senior Producer**

#### Corbis, Inc.

Feb 2000 - May 2006

Managed technical delivery of new Corbis Motion e-licensing platform and multiple online marketing campaigns. Designed, built, and deployed a Perl-based **content management and localisation product** enabling localised delivery of an E-Commerce platform with \$13M annual turn-over to five markets in under two weeks. **Flash, ActionScript, ASP.NET, SQLServer, Perl, HTML, and JavaScript.** 

Additional experience available upon request

#### **Education**

#### University of Colorado at Boulder, USA

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Design (Architecture) - 3.75 GPA

Additional coursework in computer science

#### Rhode Island School of Design, USA

European Honors Program (EHP) Art History/Architecture studio - 4.0 GPA

Additional courses, certifications, and conferences available upon request

## **Miscellany**

Dual-national (US & UK). Musician, composer, abstract artist, and conversational French-speaker. Self-appointed world diplomat. Able to leap tall buildings in a single bound.

Learn more at http://www.peterkappus.com